A Guide to the Papers of Dolley Madison, 1794-1849, n.d.
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Dolley Madison 1794-1849, n.d.
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Various Accessions
ca. 182 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Biographical/Historical Information
Dolley Payne Todd Madison (May 20, 1768 - July 12, 1849), wife of President James Madison, who served from 1809 until 1817. She also occasionally acted as First Lady during the administration of Thomas Jefferson, fulfilling the ceremonial functions more usually associated with the President's wife, since Jefferson was a widower.
She was born in New Garden, a Quaker community in what is today Guilford County, North Carolina, on May 20, 1768, a daughter of John Payne, a not-too-successful farmer and erstwhile starch manufacturer, and his wife, Mary Coles. She spent her teenage years in Philadelphia, where she married John Todd, Jr. (January 7, 1790), a lawyer who was instrumental in keeping her father out of bankruptcy and who found Mary Payne a position as the manager of a boarding house. The couple had two sons, John Payne Todd (1792-1852) and William Temple Todd (b./d. 1793). Her husband and their younger child died in 1793 in a yellow fever epidemic.
Dolley Todd married James Madison on September 14, 1794. The couple were introduced by Aaron Burr, a mutual friend, who was a frequent guest at the boarding house managed by Mary Payne. The location of the wedding was a Virginia plantation owned by the bride's brother-in-law George Steptoe Washington, a nephew of the first president of the United States. The Madisons had no children but raised Dolley's son from her first marriage, John Payne Todd, whom they called Payne. Unfortunately, the child grew into a profligate young man addicted to gambling, a habit that resulted in his mother's eventual impoverishment.
During her husband's political life, Dolley Madison was noted as a gracious hostess, whose ebullient personality, love of feathered turbans, and passion for snuff seemed at odds with her Quaker upbringing. However, probably her most lasting achievements were her letters to James Madison during the period of the framing of the United States Constitution, and her rescue of state papers and a Gilbert Stuart painting of George Washington from the White House before it was burned by the British army in 1814.
When James Madison's second term as president ended in 1817 the couple retired to Montpelier. Dolley loved to entertain at Montpelier and often had the house full of guests. James Madison suffered from arthritis in his later years and was unable to write so Dolley spent much of her time letting him dictate his correspondence. Not long after James died in June of 1836 Dolley left Montpelier and moved back to Washington, D.C. At her funeral in 1849, Zachary Taylor used the phrase "First Lady" to describe Dolley Madison, a term now used to describe the president's wife.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of ca. 182 items, chiefly correspondence to and from Dolley Payne Todd Madison.
Contents List
- Catharine Coles to Dolley Madison 1794 June 1, ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. with address leaf; docketed; Barrow. (Box 1)
  #1614
- P. Lyons Jr. to "Julia" 1794 July 18, ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. with address leaf, transcript included, docketed; Barrow. (Box 1)
  #1646
- Rob Honeyman to Dolley Madison 1795 January 25, ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. with address leaf; docketed; Barrow. (Box 1)
  #5834
- Dolley P. Madison to Miss Mary Eliza Coles 1797 September 7, ALS, 1 p. with address leaf; Barrow. (Box 1)
  #1729
- Barry Grove to Dolley Madison 1798 April 8, ALS, 4 p. on 1 l.; Barrow. (Box 1)
- Rob Honeyman to Dolley Madison 1799 July 19, ALS, 1 p. with address leaf; docketed; damaged; Barrow. (Box 1)
- Anna Maria Thornton to Dolley Madison 1802 August 24, ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. with address leaf; docketed. (Box 1)
- R.H. Hay to Dolley Madison 1802 December 8, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
- Dolley Madison to Anna Cutts 1804 April 26, ALS, 4 p. on 1 l.; Barrow. (Box 1)
  #1661 Tracy W. McGregor Library
- Nelly Conway Madison Willis to Dolley Madison 1804 June 3, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
  #5718
- Nelly Conway Madison Willis to Dolley Madison 1804 October 14, ALS, 4 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
- Dolley Madison to "My Beloved Sister" [Anna Cutts] [1805?] July 29, AL, 2 p. on 1 l.; Barrow. (Box 1)
- Nelly Conway Madison Willis to Dolley Madison 1805 March 15, ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
- Nelly Conway Madison Willis to Dolley Madison 1805 April 28, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
- Dolley Madison to Anna Cutts 1805 August 19, ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. with address leaf.; Barrow. (Box 1)
- William Bell to Dolley Madison 1806 July 18, ALS, 1 p. with address leaf; docketed; Barrow. (Box 1)
- Dolley Madison to Anna Cutts [1807] March 27, 3 p. on 1 l. with address leaf.; Barrow. (Box 1)
- George Watterston to Dolley Madison 1809 March 10, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
- John Goulding to Dolley Madison 1809 April 20, ALS, 1 p.; docketed. (Box 1)
- Sally Wheaton to Dolley Madison 1809 June 20, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
  #5718-b
- John Goulding to Dolley Madison 1809 October 4, ALS, 1 p.; docketed. (Box 1)
- Congressman A.J. Dalean to John Payne Dodd 181[?] March 29, ALS, 1 p. with address leaf. (Box 1)
  #8607
- David Bailie Warden to Dolley Payne Madison 1811 January 19, ALS, 1 p. (Box 1)
  #8005
- David Bailie Warden to Dolley Payne Madison 1811 March 12, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
- David Bailie Warden to Dolley Madison 1811 March 16, ALS, 1 p.; docketed. (Box 1)
- Sir Augustus John Foster to Dolley Madison 1812 January 24, ALS, 1 p. (Box 1)
- Mrs. Joel Barlow to Dolley P. Madison 1812 March 4, ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. with address leaf; docketed. (Box 1)
  #8392
- Nelly A. Willis to Dolley Madison 1812 June 24, ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. with address leaf. (Box 1)
  #3525-q
- Dolley Payne Madison to Mrs. Stevenson 1812 December 15, AL, 1 p. (Box 1)
- Dolley Madison to "My beloved sister" [Anna Cutts] [1812] March 20, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. with address leaf; docketed; damaged; Barrow. (Box 1)
- Mary E. H. Latrobe to Dolley Madison [1812] December 19, ALS, 4 p. on 1 l.; docketed. (Box 1)
  #6435
- J.S. Blount to Dolley Madison 1813 July 18, ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. with address leaf; docketed. (Box 1)
- Charles Grandeson to Dolley Madison 1813 July 26, ALS, 4 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
  #1597
- William Gamble to Dolley Madison 1814 January 4, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
- Mrs. Joel Barlow to Dolley Madison 1814 April 8, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
- Dolley Madison to Miss Maury [post 1814 October 27], ALS, Draft, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
  Written on the verso of a note from W. Dallas to the Madisons accepting their invitation dated October 27, 1814. #5718-b
- David Bailie Warden to John Payne Todd 1815 May 2, ALS, 1 p. with address leaf. (Box 1)
- David Bailie Warden to John Payne Todd 1815 June 20, ALS, 1 p. address leaf. (Box 1)
- David Bailie Warden to John Payne Todd 1815 September 23, ALS, 1 p. with address leaf. (Box 1)
- Dolley Payne Madison to Edward Coles 1816 July 1, ALS, 1 p. (Box 1)
- George Boyd to Dolley Madison 1816 September 2, ALS, 2 p. (Box 1)
- David Bailie Warden to Dolley Payne Madison 1816 October 4, ALS, 1 p. (Box 1)
- C.N. O'Brien to Dolley Madison 1819 December 27, ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. with address leaf; docketed; Barrow. (Box 1)
- Dolley Coles Winston to Dolley Madison 181[?] February, ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
- Dolley Madison to John Payne Todd 1823 April 12, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. with address leaf; docketed. (Box 1)
  #6078
- Catharine B. [F]arish to Dolley Madison 1830 January 6, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
- Dolley Madison to "My Dear Sister" 1830 January 25, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l.; Barrow. (Box 1)
- Dolley Payne Madison to Ann Maury 1831 August 8, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. with address leaf. (Box 1)
  #3888
- Dolley Madison to Mrs. Francis Lear 1832 February 14, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. with address leaf. (Box 1)
  #7879
- 1833 November 27, ALS, 8 p. on 2 l. Incomplete. (Box 1)
- Dolley Madison to Ellen Cutts 1834 January 25, ALS, 1 p.; silked. (Box 1)
  #11387
- Richard Cutts to Dolley Madison 1835 June 24, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
- Dolley Madison to Ann Maury 1836 March 22, ALS, 1 p.; transcript included. (Box 1)
  #11574
- Dolley Madison to Mrs. Virginia Frist 1836 April 28, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. with address leaf; docketed. (Box 1)
  #5385-N
- Sarah C. Stevenson to Dolley Payne Madison 1836 May 30, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. with address leaf; docketed. (Box 1)
- Dolley Madison to Richard Cutts 1836 July 5, ALS, 1 p. with address leaf. (Box 1)
  #10029-e
- George Tucker to Dolley Madison 1836 July 25, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. with address leaf; docketed. (Box 1)
  #8332 Clifton Waller Barrett Library
- Sarah Coles Stevenson to Dolley Madison 1836 July 26, ALS, 4 p. on 1 l. with address leaf; docketed. (Box 1)
  #3991
- Dolley Madison to Messrs. Harper [post 1836 August 17], ALS, Draft, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
- George A. Smith to Dolley Madison 1836, ALS, 1 p. with address leaf; docketed. (Box 1)
  #8707 Madison citizens send a copy of resolutions on death of James Madison.
- Financial documents signed by Dolley Madison as Executrix of James Madison 1836-1838, 8 ADS. (Box 1)
  Documents include orders on the cashier of the Branch Bank of Virginia at Fredericksburg for payments designated in the will of James Madison to his niece, Rebecca Chapman, and his nephews, James Madison Hite, Erasmus T. Rose, Conway C. Macon, Henry Macon, Cattell Madison, and William Madison, all dated 1836; an order on the cashier of the Branch Bank of Virginia at Fredericksburg for payment to Eliza Madison, guardian of the three sons of Robert S. Madison, June 3, 1837; and a promissory note drawn to the order of and endorsed by J.M. Cutts, May 23, 1838. #5718-a
- Invitations and social notes addressed to Dolley Madison and family 1836-1849, n.d., 7 items. (Box 1)
- Dolley Madison to James H. Causten, Jr. 1837 January 12, ALS, 1 p. with address leaf. (Box 1)
  #11374
- Dolley P. Madison to John Forsyth 1837 April 1, ALS (draft), 2 p. on 1 l.; damaged. (Box 1)
- Receipt to Dolley Madison signed by Isaac Beeson 1837 September 12, ADS, 1 p. (Box 1)
- E. Wirt to Dolley Madison 1837 October 9, ALS, 1 p. (Box 1)
- Dolley P. Madison to [?] 1838 April 3, ALS, 1 p. (Box 1)
  #2432
- Dolley Madison to James Newman 1838 May 25, ALS, 1 p. with address leaf; docketed. (Box 1)
  #7650
- Dolley Madison to Mrs. L. Henry Cutts 1838 October 8, ALS, 1 p. with address leaf; Barrow. (Box 1)
- Dolley P. Madison to Mr. Wertenbaker 1838 October 27, ALS, 1 p. with address leaf; docketed. (Box 1)
  RG-5/3
- George Tucker to Dolly Payne Madison 1838 December 28, ALS, 1 p.; docketed. (Box 1)
- 10 invitations and 3 tickets to various balls 1838-1847, Printed Items. (Box 1)
  #8607 Invitations to Carusi's May Balle, Washington Assemblies (1842), Washington Assemblies (1845), Washington Assemblies (1846), Washington Assemblies (1847), 3 tickets to Carusi's Ball, 2 invitations to The National Birth Night Ball, National Birth Night Assembly, Carusi's May Ball (1846 May 7) and the Bachelor's Ball (1838 March 22)
- Dolley Madison to Mrs. Lucy H. Conway 1839 February 2, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
  #9562
- Dolley Madison to Mrs. James K. Paulding 1839 October 28, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
  #2378
- Dolley Madison to Mrs. Ellicott 1839 February 8, ALS, 1 p. (Box 1)
- [Frances Dandridge] Lear to Dolley Madison 1839 September 22, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
- Richard Cutts to Dolley Madison 183[?] August 20, ALS, 1 p. (Box 1)
  #5482-b
- Edward Everett to Dolley Madison 1840 February 15, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
  #8700
- Dolley Madison Septimia Randolph 1840 August 31, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. with address leaf; docketed; Barrow. (Box 1)
  #4726-a
- Dolley Madison to Richard Smith 1840 December 10, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. (Box 1)
- Envelopes franked by Dolley Madison 1840, 14 items (Box 1)
- Anna Payne and Dolly Madison on James Madison's notes on the Constitution [ca. 1840], AM, 3 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
  #1342
- Dolley P. Madison to Joseph Cabell 1841 March 30, ALS, 1 p. with address leaf; docketed. (Box 1)
  #2737
- Dolley Madison to Mr. Sioussa 1841 June 2, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
  #5327-b
- Joseph C. Cabell to Dolley Payne Madison 1841 June 24, ALS, 1 p. (Box 1)
- Dolley Madison Manuscripts on Finances 1841-1848, ADS, 9 items (Box 1)
  #4889
- Dolley Madison to Eliza Collins Lee 1842 March 21, ALS, 1 p. with address leaf. (Box 1)
  #12041
- E[lizabeth Collins] Lee to [Anthony Morris] 1843 August 4, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l.; transcript included. (Box 1)
  #4906
- Dolley Madison to Septimia Randolph 1844 December 5, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. (Box 1)
- Ellen Cutts to "My dear friend" [Septimia Randolph Meikleham] 1845 October 12, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box 1)
- Dolley Madison to Martha H. Cutts 1846 February 15, ALS, 1 p.; photocopy. (Box 1)
  #5756
- Quotation signed by Dolley Madison 1846 March 20, AMS, 1 p. (Box 1)
  #8627
- Dolley Madison poem to Mrs. Hathaway 1846 March 27, MS, 1 p. (Box 1)
  #2905
- J.S. Barbour to Dolley Madison 1846 November 30, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
  #8707
- S.M. to Dolley Madison 1847 January 1, ALS, 1 p. (Box 1)
- Dolley Payne Madison to James Buchanan 1847 February 3, ALS, 1 p. with address leaf. (Box 1)
  #1714 [Recommends Mr. Corcoran as a candidate for the army or a civil appointment]
- C.M.[F] Smith to Dolley Madison 1847 October 10, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. with address leaf. (Box 1)
- Dolley Madison to "Dr. Winston" 1848 November 28, ALS, 1 p. with address leaf. (Box 1)
  #10090
- C.S. Todd to Dolley Madison 1849 May 21, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
- C.S. Todd to Dolley Madison 1849 May 26, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
- C.S. Todd to Dolley Madison 1849 June 4, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
- Will of Dolley Madison 1849 June 11, AMS, 3 p. on 3 l.; photocopy. (Box 1)
  #2988
- Elizabeth Collins Lee to Zaccheus Collins Lee [ca. 1849], AL, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
- Maria Keene to Dolley Madison n.y. February 8, ALS, 1 p. with address leaf; docketed. (Box 1)
  #5834 Letter of introduction for Mrs. Benaudebt
- Martha Winston to Dolley Madison n.y. March 17, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
- Mrs. F. P. Blair to Dolley Madison n.y. April 8, ALS, 1 p. (Box 1)
  #9753
- Nelly Conway Madison Willis to Dolley Madison n.y. April 27, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
- John Steele to Dolley Madison n.y. October 2, John Steele to Dolley Madison (Box 1)
- Eliza Harwood to Dolley Madison n.y. December 9, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box 1)
- [?] to Dolley Madison n.d., ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. (Box 2)
- M.E. Van Ness to Dolley Madison n.d., ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. with address leaf. (Box 2)
- Ellen Fletcher to Dolley Madison n.d., ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. (Box 2)
- Mary J. Wethered to Dolley Madison n.d., ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box 2)
- M.W. Van Zandt to Dolley Madison n.d., ALS, 1 p. with address leaf. (Box 2)
- M.W. Van Zandt to Dolley Madison n.d., ALS, 1 p. (Box 2)
- Julia Tayloe to Dolley Madison n.d. February 12, ALS, 1 p. with address leaf. (Box 2)
- Julia Tayloe to Dolley Madison n.d. September 6, ALS, 1 p. with address leaf. (Box 2)
- Julia Tayloe to Dolley Madison n.d., ALS, 1 p. with address leaf. (Box 2)
- Julia Tayloe to Dolley Madison n.d., ALS, 1 p. (Box 2)
- Julia Tayloe to Dolley Madison n.d., ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. with address leaf. (Box 2)
- Julia Tayloe to Dolley Madison n.d., ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. with address leaf. (Box 2)
- Julia Tayloe to Dolley Madison n.d., ALS, 1 p. with address leaf. (Box 2)
- Virginia Tayloe to Dolley Madison n.d., ALS, 1 p. (Box 2)
- Virginia Tayloe to Dolley Madison n.d., ALS, 1 p. (Box 2)
- D.P.M Cutts (nephew of Dolley Madison) to John Payne Todd n.d., ALS, 1 p. with address leaf. (Box 2)
- Lucy H. Cutts to John Payne Todd n.d., ALS, 1 p. with address leaf. (Box 2)
- Annie Payne (adopted daughter of President and Mrs. Madison) n.d., ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. with address leaf. (Box 2)
- Invitation requesting the presence of Dolley Madison at Mr. F.C. Labbe's Ball n.d. May 6, Printed, 1 p. (Box 2)
- Invitation requesting the presence of Dolley Madison at Mr. F.C. Labbe's Ball n.d. May 12, Printed, 1 p. (Box 2)
- Mrs. J.K. Paulding to Dolley Madison n.d. April 15, ALS, 4 p. on 1 l. (Box 2)
- Theodosia David to Dolley Madison n.d., ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box 2)
- W.C. Rives to Dolley Madison n.d., ALS, 1 p. with address leaf. (Box 2)
- Mr. and Mrs. Polk n.d., AL, 1 p. with address leaf. (Box 2)
- Dolley Madison to Septimia Randolph n.d., ALS, 1 p. (Box 2)
- Dolley Madison to Eliza Rankin n.d., ALS, 2 p. on 1 l.; Barrow. (Box 2)
  #7183
- Dolley Madison to Mrs. Eliza C. Rankin n.d., ALS, 3 p. on 2 l. with address leaf.; Barrow. (Box 2)
- Quotations signed by Dolley Madison n.d., AMS, 2 p. on 2 l. (Box 2)
- William Wilkins to Dolley Madison n.d., AL(fragment), 3 p. on 2 l. with address leaf fragment; Barrow. (Box 2)
  #6564
- Quotation signed by Dolley Madison n.d., AMS, 1 p. (Box 2)
- Dolley Madison to [?] n.d., AL (fragment), 2 p. on 1 l.; Barrow. (Box 2)
  #1636
- Dolley Madison to Mrs. O'Sullivan n.d., ALS, 1 p. with address leaf. (Box 2)
  #6724
- E.K. Hay to Dolley Madison n.d., ALS, 2 p. on 1 l.; docketed. (Box 2)
- Lucy Lyons Hopkins to Dolley Madison n.d., ALS, 1 p. with address leaf; docketed. (Box 2)
- A.M. Mason to Dolley Madison n.d., ALS, 1 p.; docketed; Barrow. (Box 2)
- John Stockton Littell to Dolley Madison n.d., ALS, 1 p. (Box 2)
- Quotation written by Dolley Madison n.d., AMS, 1 p. (Box 2)
  #6539
- James Madison to Dolley Madison n.d., ALS, 1 p. with address leaf; photocopy. (Box 2)
- Dolley Payne Madison to John Payne Todd n.d., ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box 2)
- Dolley Madison, to "My Dear Sir" n.d. May 5, AL, 2 p. on 1 l.; Barrow. (Box 2)
- Dolley Madison to Mrs. Thornton n.d. May 18, ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. with address leaf. (Box 2)
- Dolley Madison to [Anna Cutts] n.d. May 18, ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. (3rd p. and address leaf fragment); Barrow. (Box 2)
- Dolley Madison to Anna Cutts n.d. June 3, ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. with address leaf; Barrow. (Box 2)
- Dolley Madison to Anna Cutts n.d. July 8, ALS, 4 p. on 2 l.; Barrow. (Box 2)
- Dolley Madison to Mrs. Van Zandt n.d. August 2, ALS, 1 p. with address leaf; Barrow. (Box 2)
- Dolley Madison to Mrs. Van Zandt n.d. August 29, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. with address leaf; Barrow. (Box 2)
- Dolley Madison to Mrs. Van Zandt n.d. September 12, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. with address leaf; Barrow. (Box 2)
- Dolley Madison to Mrs. Anna P. Cutts n.d. Tuesday, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. with address leaf; Barrow. (Box 2)
- D.P.M. Cutts to Septimia [Randolph Meikleham] n.y. October 29, ALS, 1 p. (Box 2)
- Dolley Madison to "My Beloved Sister" n.d. Friday, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l.; Barrow. (Box 2)
- Dolley Madison to "My Dear Sister" n.d., ALS, 1 p. (Box 2)
- Dolley Madison frank on a letter from E.E. Cutts to Rebecca Todd n.d., ALS, 1 p. with address leaf. (Box 2)
  #12052
- Account of Dolley Madison with Colonel Peyton n.d., AMS, 1 p. (Box 2)
- Six Miscellaneous Invitations sent to Dolley Madison n.d., Printed, 6 items. (Box 2)
  #8607 Invitations from the Sisters of the Visitation Annual Distribution of Premiums, Mrs. Cutts, The Secretary of State and Mrs. Steward, The Firemen's Ball Given by the Perseverance Fire Company, Miss Tayloe to the Octagon, and Mr. and Mrs. Van Zandt.
- [Mrs.?] Adams to Dolley Madison n.d., ALS, 8 p. on 2 l. Incomplete. (Box 2)
- Mrs. [J.S.?] Blunt to Dolley Madison n.d., ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box 2)
- [B.H.?] Latrobe to Dolley Madison n.d., ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box 2)
- Lucy Coles Winston and Martha Winston to Dolley Madison n.d., ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. (Box 2)